templeandwebster.com.au 2015-12-07

# Privacy Policy - Temple & Webster

Welcome to Temple & Webster. We’re happy to have you here.

Temple & Webster is committed to protecting and respecting your privacy.

### About this Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy is intended to inform you of our practices regarding the collection, use and disclosure of any information we collect from or about you, whether through the Temple & Webster web site or by any other method.

By visiting and/or becoming a member of the Temple & Webster web site you expressly consent to the collection, use and disclosure of your personal information in accordance with this Privacy Policy, which forms part of the Terms and Conditions of Use of our web site.

### What information we collect, and how we collect it

**Personal information**   
We collect personal information about you that you submit to us voluntarily through our web site or otherwise, for example when you apply to become a member, when you make a purchase, when you update your ‘My Account’ details, when you fill in a form on our web site or send us an email or letter, and when you enter a promotion or competition. This personal information may include (but is not limited to) your name, your email address, your postal and billing addresses, your telephone number(s) and your payment information, which may include credit card details.

We may also request further optional information such as your date or year of birth, your gender and/or other demographic information and your personal preferences. We may also collect personal information about you which you submit voluntarily by posting a comment on our blog or on our Facebook page. We advise you to limit the personal information that you publish in this way, since we cannot control any third party collection or use of any such information.

We may also collect personal information about you through third parties, for example if we purchase access to a database to which you have provided your personal information and consented to its disclosure.

**Non-personal information**   
We may collect non-personal information relating to your use of our web site. This might include (but is not limited to) your IP address, browser type and operating system. We may also use tracking technology (including cookies) to collect information about the date and time of your visit to our web site and details of which pages you viewed.

Cookies are small pieces of information that a web site sends to your computer’s hard drive while you are viewing a web site. Cookies do not identify you personally, but identify your web browser. Cookies help us by providing information about how our web site is used. We may use both session cookies (which expire once you close your web browser) and persistent cookies (which stay on your computer until you delete them). Most web browsers are set to accept cookies. You can disable cookies using your web browser’s help files, but this may affect the functionality of our web site and your ability to use our services.

### Why we collect information, and how we use it

We collect your personal information for the primary purpose of facilitating your use of our web site, including your purchase of products. We use your personal information in a number of ways for this primary purpose, including (but not limited to) providing you with access to our web site, contacting you with details of our sales, processing any purchases you make and administering our dealings with you.

We also collect your personal and non-personal information in order to improve Temple & Webster by developing processes, products and services to better meet your needs. This might include de-personalising your personal information (to create anonymous information) and aggregating it along with your non-personal information for the purpose of statistical analysis. We reserve the right to use and disclose such aggregated information as we see fit, including for marketing, advertising or research purposes.

We reserve the right to use your personal information to investigate any suspected breach of any of our Terms and Conditions or if we suspect that you are or have been engaged in any unlawful activity.

### Disclosure of your information

We do not sell, rent, barter, trade or share your personal information with third parties for their advertising or direct marketing purposes.

**We may disclose your personal information in the following circumstances:**  
We may provide your personal information to third party service providers who perform functions for us or provide services to us, for example processing credit card transactions, sending emails, marketing or analysing data. In such cases, we take steps to ensure that our service providers do not use any personal information disclosed to them except for the purposes of providing the requested service to us.

If you choose to log in to our web site using your Facebook log in details, we may need to share your email address (in encrypted format) with Facebook for the sole purpose of allowing us to match your Temple & Webster account with your Facebook account.

We may disclose your personal information to the police or any relevant authority or enforcement body (including your internet service provider) if we suspect you are in breach of our Terms and Conditions of Use or that you are or have been engaged in any unlawful activity and we reasonably believe this disclosure is necessary, or if required to do so by law. We may disclose your personal information as part of a sale or proposed sale of our business.

### Third parties

Our web site may contain links to third party web sites, including Facebook and other social media web sites.

We are not responsible for the privacy practices of other web sites and this Privacy Policy does not apply to any third party web sites.

### Security

We employ appropriate electronic and procedural measures to protect personal information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. When you purchase from Temple & Webster, your financial details are passed through a secure server using the latest industry standard 256-bit SSL (secure sockets layer) encryption technology. Access to your personal information is limited to employees we believe reasonably need to use that information in order to perform their roles in providing or developing our services.

You acknowledge that despite our best efforts the security of online transactions and communications sent by electronic means or by post cannot be guaranteed.

### Opting out

You may opt out of receiving promotional communications from us at any time. Each time you receive a promotional communication, it will include instructions about how to unsubscribe from future promotional communications.

Alternatively you can contact us directly at [privacy@templeandwebster.com.au](mailto:privacy@templeandwebster.com.au?subject=Privacy%20enquiry%20via%20Privacy%20Policy). Even if you opt out of receiving promotional communications, you may still receive communications from us, for example administrative communications related to a purchase you make, or service announcements.

### Changes to this Privacy Policy

We may update this Privacy Policy from time to time by updating this page. Continued use of our web site following such changes indicates your agreement to be bound by the updated Privacy Policy.

### Contacting us and updating personal information

You may view and update your personal information at any time in the “My Account” section of our web site.

If you wish to cancel your membership and remove your personal information from our database (other than for legitimate record-keeping or business reasons), or if you have any questions or concerns about your privacy, you can contact us by email at [privacy@templeandwebster.com.au](mailto:privacy@templeandwebster.com.au?subject=Privacy%20enquiry%20via%20Privacy%20Policy)

### Company details

Temple & Webster Pty Ltd  
ABN 65 151 856 049  
8DD Hiles St Alexandria NSW 2015 Australia  
Telephone 02 9698 4548   
Fax 02 9698 4568   
Email [support@templeandwebster.com.au](mailto:support@templeandwebster.com.au?subject=Enquiry%20via%20Terms%20page "Click here to send an email to Temple & Webster support")

Last updated: 24th February 2012
